#### VICENTE LLANOS

# 264 Gowan Avenue, East York, ON, M4J 2K6 Mobile: (416) 662-2441

vicentellanos@hotmail.com

Online Resume: <a href="http://www.vicentellanos.owlinternet.net/">http://www.vicentellanos.owlinternet.net/</a>

### PERSONAL SUMMARY

A talented systems engineer and software developer with a strong academic background, exceptional analytical, design and problem-solving capabilities. Over one year of experience in the software development industry plus 6 years of experience in the areas of the computer networking and computer troubleshooting. Excellent communication skills and able to work alongside other professionals. A proven ability to maintain and enhance company software with the aim of improving operational functionality in line with business requirement.

Looking for an ambitious company that provides an opportunity for growth and where my developer and problem solving skills allow me to become a valuable asset.

## **EDUCATION**

Seneca College

DATABASE APPLICATION DEVELOPER GRADUATE CERTIFICATE (GPA: 3.9/4.0)

High Honours

Toronto, Ontario
2015-2016

Synergy Business College Toronto, Ontario
INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY (Post-Secondary) Diploma (GPA: 3.3/4.0) 2007-2009

Niagara College Welland, Ontario
COMPUTER NETWORK OPERATIONS GRADUATE CERTIFICATE (GPA: 3.92/4.0) 2005-2006

Fundación Universitaria San Martín Sede Caribe SYSTEMS ENGINEERING BACHELOR'S DEGREE (GPA: 3.7/4.0) Barranquilla, Colombia 1997-2002

### **CONTINUING EDUCATION**

Web Development Using Java EE and Open Source Technologies Centennial College., Toronto - Canada, May 2015 - August 2015

Java Advanced Programming ( JavaFX )

Ryerson University., Toronto - Canada, September 2014 - December 2014

Java Programming Language SL-275. Dictated by Sun Microsystem

Gerentes S.A., Barranguilla - Colombia 2004

# <u>SKILLS</u>

Programming AngularJS, JavaScript, Java (Spring Boot Framework, JSP, JPA, Hibernate, Servlets, Threads, JavaFX, Swing, Struts,

JDBC, JSTL, Filters, JSF, Ajax, Sockets), Web Services (REST, SOAP), Spring MVC, Bootstrap, Groovy, Maven, HTML5, CSS, XML, JSON, C, Delphi, Visual Basic, XSLT, WML, UML (Unified Modeling Language), Bash Shell scripting, Object

Oriented Programming, PHP, awk, ASP, Prolog, Lisp, Assembler, Perl, familiar with SVN and Git,

Databases Database designing (ERD, Class Diagram, Conceptual Model), Application designing that interacts with databases,

SQL, SQL Server, familiar with T-SQL, Microsoft Access, MySQL, Oracle PL/SQL, Oracle SQL PLUS, SQL Developer,

MongoDB, DBeaver, Robomongo.

Networking LAN configuration, Active Directory, Group Policy, TCP/IP, WINS, DNS, DHCP, VPN, NAT, ICS, IP Addressing and

Subnetting, Routing Protocols, Terminal Services, NFS (Linux), Samba, Wireless Networking.

Software / MS Office, MS Visio, Rational Rose, Oracle VM VirtualBox, VMWare, Eclipse, IntelliJ, Sublime, NetBeans, Apache Hardware Tomcat, SourceTree, SOAP UI, WinSCP, Putty, Jenkins, JIRA, BitBucket, Microsoft Windows 9X/2000/XP/7/Server

2003 and Unix/Linux.

Computer installation, configuration, troubleshooting repair and maintenance procedures.

LANGUAGES English (Proficient) Spanish (Native) German (Basic)

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

TECHNITASK Toronto, Ontario March 2017-July 2017

# Junior Full Stack Developer

**Enviornment:** Java, AngularJS, Spring MVC, IntelliJ IDEA, Eclipse, HTML5, CSS, Bootstrap, Web Services (REST, SOAP), JSON, XML, Maven, Git, SourceTree, BitBucket, SOAP UI, Selenium WebDriver, Thucydides (Serenity), JUnit, TestNG, JIRA, WinSCP, Putty, Sketch.

**Description:** MELT (Mandatory Entry Level Training) variation project for the Ministry Of Transportation of Ontario (MTO). The purpose of this project was to make changes in existing multiple applications including CSA application (Customer service agent), Scheduler, Drivetest.ca, Qmatic application, IVR, CVOR (Commercial vehicle operator registration) to fulfill driver's examination new rules and requirements. In addition to the previous applications, changes to the services that were part of the system were also made. (Unified, Rules and Audit services).

- Wrote the respective unit tests for the changes made in the different applications using TestNG.
- Implemented different SOAP Web Services according to the company needs.
- Created a tool that was used to show the version of each of the components that were deployed in the different development environments (DEV, UAT, VQA).
- Created User Interface Mockups using Sketch and generated class diagrams with IntelliJ.
- Set up Jenkins, Apache Tomcat, Git, Maven, JDK in a Linux server (Fedora), deployed web applications and checked Tomcat logs to identify and resolve errors.
- Used the Selenium WebDriver and JUnit frameworks for Test Case automation using Java.
- Participated in Daily Stand up Team meetings to discuss daily status and gueries.

MUNICIPAL PROPERTY ASSESSMENT CORPORATION Pickering, Ontario May 2016- Dec 2016

## IT Systems Developer Co-op

**Environment:** Java, AngularJS, Javascript, HTML5, CSS, Bootstrap, RESTful Web Services, MongoDB, Spring Boot Framework, Maven, Groovy, MySQL, Oracle, JSON, XML, Git, SVN.

- Implented new modules for a portal that the company uses to collect data from the property owners of Ontario. PIER web application.
- Implemented a tool ( web application ) for the future use of the company that would help automate a process that had been previously done manually. Suppression tool ( Tool used to suppress properties from the mail-out).
- Made improvements to a company's application that was used to collect data about the different properties in Ontario. PIER B2B.

Barranquilla, Colombia Jan 2010 - Nov 2013

#### Freelance Computer Technician

• Installed, repaired, maintained, and upgraded desktop and notebook computers.

EXCEL SYSTEMS CANADA Toronto, Ontario Aug 2006 - Jul 2007

#### **Network Administrator Assistant**

- Installed various software and hardware on the computer systems. Provided technical support.
- Assisted in server and network administration by installing patches and configuring user accounts.

SAI BOSTON Barranquilla, Colombia Sept 2004 - July 2005

# Computer Technician/Customer Service

- Provided technical support to users experiencing difficulties with computer hardware and software.
- Maintained the use of the local area network (LAN), hardware, software and related computers.

I.S.M COMPUTADORES E.U Barranguilla, Colombia

Feb 2003 - Jan 2004

# Computer Programmer

**Environment:** Delphi and Microsoft Access.

Wrote, modified, integrated and tested software code. Maintained the existing computer program by
making modifications as required. Prepared reports, manuals and other documentation on the status,
operation and maintenance of software.

# **ACHIEVEMENTS**

President's Honour List - Winter term

Seneca College, 2016

• President's Honour Roll - Fall-Winter term

Niagara College, 2005-2006

APICE Graduate Program Scholarship

Niagara College, 2005

Third ranked student in the graduation class

Fundación Universitaria San Martín Sede Caribe Barranquilla, 2002

• Scholarship awarded

Fundación Universitaria San Martín Sede Caribe Barranquilla, 2001